Dad.
Wake up.
I must've drifted off.
Where were we?
- The madman.
- Oh.
Of course.
The Hatter...
who says,
"If I had a world of my own,
everything would be nonsense.
Nothing would be what it is
because everything
would be what it isn't."
Everything would be what it isn't?
Even me.
Hey.
You're perfect.
You're gonna beat this.
Hmm?
I promise you.
Now, let's skip to something fun.
Dad.
- What is it, Charlie?
- Listen to me.
Listen.
Charlie?
Charlie!
And finally, have you ever
questioned the nature of your reality?
No.
Good.
Now, then, I see you had
a blacklisted exchange with a guest
in the course of your narrative.
Can you tell me what happened?
He said he wanted to
cut off a piece of me
to take home in his carry-on,
that he wanted to mount
it on the hood of his car
for his friends to see.
I told him if he wanted a trophy,
I could cut pieces of him off and
let him fish for them in the Olvido.
And did this exchange make you
question anything about your world?
No.
This world is as doomed as ever.
And just for my peace of mind...
Anything about these images
that jumps out to you?
They don't look like anything to me.
We're through 15% of the backlog.
As it stands, we should be
caught up by end of day.
- Good.
- And, uh, when you're done here, sir,
there's a priority request
for him from management.
Have you seen Elsie?
She was supposed to give
me a hand on something.
No. Uh, according to the system,
she started her leave today.
Is there something I could help you with?
No, thanks.
Raise.
I'll call.
You're calling with that shit?
Dolores, why don't you play a hand?
You're wasting your breath.
Girl's harboring a grudge.
I don't blame you, sweetheart.
I did some ugly things to you both.
But it wasn't personal.
Confederados and the government
like to call this thing a war,
but they're fighting starving farmers
armed with rocks.
That ain't no war.
It's a slaughter.
If I had to do it all again,
I'd fuck you both over just as hard.
Well, I guess we know where you stand.
Don't pretend like you're so innocent.
Way I recollect, y'all came to me,
looking to join up with those crooked
assholes and their war effort.
Not our idea.
My friend wanted...
I guess he wanted to see what
was at the end of all this.
And yet, here you are.
Your friend didn't make it this far.
Maybe you've got more of an
appetite for this than you think.
William.
What is it?
We're in Ghost Nation territory.
Most savage tribe there is.
Those are the folks who came
calling without an invitation.
You mean exactly what
we're doing right now?
The train's the only way through.
On foot we'll be dead in under an hour.
As soon as we're clear of
their territory, we can stop.
You can come with me.
Nothing here on out but slaughter.
The user you are trying
to access cannot be located.
Say "message" to transcribe a message.
You wanted to see me? Is everything okay?
You left rather abruptly last night.
Was there something
you wanted to tell me?
No, I don't think so.
Hale is looking over every department
and yours is running
behind on diagnostics.
It would be best if we presented
at least a semblance of professionalism
while the board is here.
We'll be fine.
My people know how to do their jobs.
If they applied half as
much energy to their work
as they have to second-guessing
my team's investigation...
That's all over.
Are you sure?
Yes.
Good.
You doing okay?
I'm fine. Thank you.
I'm sorry. I thought
you requested a meeting.
- My mistake.
- I did.
Come in.
Get back here.
Bring your friend.
What about you? What turns of fate...
I could come back later
if this isn't a good time.
This won't take long.
Theresa, you've always
been good at your job
and the board has been impressed
with your performance so far,
which is why we were so surprised
by this woodcutter mess.
A small setback.
He slipped on a fucking rock
and bashed his own head in
while basically on top of a behavior tech.
Meanwhile, Ford is suddenly
using half the park's resources
to build some new narrative?
Can I bum a cigarette?
God, I see why you took these up again.
Let me remind you of something.
This place, the people who
work here are nothing.
Our interest in this place is
entirely in the intellectual property.
The code.
The hosts' minds, the storylines...
I don't give a rat's ass about the hosts.
It's our little research
project that Delos cares about.
That's where the real value is.
And due to a lack of foresight
on part of one of my predecessors,
35 years of information...
Raw information... Exists here.
Nowhere else.
Ford has always ensured that.
Now, you are a smart enough woman.
Tell me, why would we need
you to secure all of it?
Because you're going to fire him.
You don't fire someone
who created an empire.
You ask him to retire politely.
And if that person has the
ability to snap his fingers
and erase the value of that empire,
you have to make sure
you have a contingency.
So, you and I need to ensure
that by the time the rest
of the board arrives,
we are on course for that transition.
Okay?
I like you.
Well, not personally,
but I like you for this job,
which is why I'm gonna
give you another chance
to get a handle on this
particular bitch of a situation.
But the gods...
they require a blood sacrifice.
We need to demonstrate
just how dangerous
Ford's creations can be.
No.
No, nothing so obvious.
We need someone thoroughly unexpected.
I told you never open
your mouth that wide
unless someone's paying you for it.
Sorry, Maeve.
I didn't sleep much last night.
What are these nightmares you have about?
Do you ever dream you're someone else?
I don't think so.
Why?
You ever thought about whether
this is really the life you want?
I don't intend to make this my life's work.
No offense.
Mm.
My family's got a farm.
Bad soil. Nothing grows.
I send money back to them.
They think I work in a dress shop.
What's wrong?
I'm just doing what you told me to.
A couple more years of this and...
then I can have whatever life I want.
I'm gonna get my family
out of the desert.
We're gonna go somewhere...
cold.
Someday.
Which one is it?
It's the one at the bar. Go.
Quick, before the guests
upstairs finish up.
Whatever she did, it must've been serious
if they're making us grab
her in broad daylight.
We got her. Let's go.
You're supposed to be resting.
We're riding a train full with
explosives through scalping territory.
Not sleepy.
Can I ask you something?
This place you're looking for,
what makes you so sure it exists?
I'm not.
My life before, I was
so sure of the world.
But now it feels like a lie.
Only thing I know is whatever's
out there, I'm never going back.
What is it you're looking for?
Lawrence is right.
You could've stayed in
Pariah or gone back,
but you're here.
With me.
The only thing I had when
I was a kid were books.
I used to live in them.
I used to go to sleep
dreaming I'd wake up
inside one of them
'cause they had meaning.
This place, this is like I woke
up inside one of those stories.
I guess I just wanna find
out what it means.
I don't wanna be in a story.
All I want is to not look forward or back.
I just wanna be...
in the moment I'm in.
Dolores,
back home, there's a woman, Juliet,
and her father owns the
company where I work.
She's, uh, Logan's sister.
Yeah.
And when I get home,
we're getting married.
Oh.
The place you're after,
I will help you find it.
But I can't stay.
I have a life waiting for me.
I'm sorry.
Of course.
Dolores.
I've been pretending my whole life.
Pretending I don't mind,
pretending I belong.
My life's built on it.
And it's a good life.
It's a life I've always wanted.
But then I came here
and I get a glimpse for a second
of a life in which
I don't have to pretend.
A life in which I can be truly alive.
How can I go back to pretending
when I know what this feels like?
Miss Hale.
I was not aware those
with your level of insight
needed any more reflection.
Dr. Ford. Always charming.
What is this?
Apparently, Miss Cullen and Miss Hale
have a presentation for us.
What about?
Following the recent
reports of host malfunction,
we asked QA to check the
last abortive update,
which featured the reveries,
- as I believe they're called.
- Mm-hmm.
I'm sorry to report that
Miss Cullen and her team
uncovered some worrisome findings.
In the course of our code review,
we found something quite disturbing.
Wake her up.
We set Clementine Pennyfeather
back to her previous update.
When we discovered the build was buggy
due to a last-minute
injection of the reverie code,
we quickly rolled all the infected
hosts back to their prior builds.
Mm, you're new.
Not much of a rind on you.
No!
No! No!
No, no.
No, no, no...
Please. Please.
Help me!
Please, please, please!
- No!
- All right, that's enough.
Freeze.
As you've no doubt gathered,
our tech is, in fact, a host.
One that has been coded for
the purposes of this simulation
to read as a human.
And as you can see, behavioral safeguards
are operating exactly
as you would expect.
Reset her. Wipe her memory.
Okay, let's do this again.
You're new.
Not much of a rind on you.
That's enough, sweetheart.
That's enough.
Freeze all motor functions.
In each case we examined,
the malfunctioning hosts
were not resetting properly.
The retention of data
that hadn't been wiped
overloaded their
decision-making apparatus,
eventually causing a system failure
that allowed for override
of their primary rule set.
The concern with the reveries
is that the hosts will remember
some of their experiences
and act on them.
You're telling us that these hosts
were responding to a grudge?
That's exactly what I'm saying, Mr. Lowe.
And funny you should use that
particular word, "grudge,"
since what was most troubling to me
was that several techs in behavior
voiced these exact same concerns
to the head of their department.
You put this code out
without proper vetting
and without reasonable
understanding of its ramifications.
So, either you didn't write it
or you're getting sloppy
to the point of risking
the lives of our guests.
Few things surprise me anymore, Mr. Lowe,
but this level of negligence
is fucking breathtaking.
We are way beyond rollback territory.
Within the next six months,
we'll need to rebuild the hosts
from the ground up.
You want us to lobotomize
them is what you're saying.
No, not you, Mr. Lowe.
After all, this was your responsibility,
assuming that you have
nothing to share with us
in terms of your culpability.
No.
Then you're fired.
Hey.
Morning, William.
I... I didn't wanna wake you.
I know...
last night was unexpected.
If you regret it...
I don't regret a thing.
I know you have someone
waiting for you at home.
All that feels so unreal now.
I used to think this
place was all about...
pandering to your baser instincts.
Now I understand.
It doesn't cater to your lowest self,
it reveals your deepest self.
It shows you who you really are.
You remember the look on Logan's
face when we left him behind?
Do you know how long
I've wanted to do that,
to let him know what I think of him?
And you, last night,
I've never felt that way before,
not with any woman.
You've unlocked something in me.
I'm not a key, William.
I'm just me.
What is that?
I don't know.
At home, I used to paint.
Landscapes mostly,
but I was always just...
copying the world outside me.
This morning, I woke up and I thought...
"What if I drew something new?"
I imagined something beautiful.
A place where the mountains meet the sea.
Everyone who comes here is longing
for excitement or conflict,
and you're just...
dreaming of the opposite.
Well, what about you, William?
What do you dream of?
Yah!
What is it?
- Ambush.
- Is it the Ghost Nation?
Worse. The Confederados.
Fucking coward.
Vaya con dios, motherfuckers.
They're making a run for it!
Come on, boys, get up!
Come on, stay close!
Ah!
Go, boys!
Yah!
Dolores!
Go, go! Take 'em down!
Go, go!
Ghost Nation!
Ah!
Let's go!
Stop, William! Stop!
It's real...
what I dreamt.
It's the place you drew.
You coming?
Once the Ghosts is done acquainting
themselves with those poor bastards,
they'll be coming after us.
My friends here are itching
to join the war effort.
Think I've had enough of war.
How about you?
You got a knack for killing.
I'm afraid this is where we part ways.
Careful.
If you're heading west across that river,
you may be leaving the fighting behind,
but you're gonna be in
unclaimed territories.
What's out that way?
You're gonna have to ask the dust.
Ain't nothing ever come back from there.
We're almost done here.
Why don't I close up?
You've been topside
for less than 24 hours.
You keep coming down this often,
people are going to notice.
- Where's Clem?
- I don't know.
I haven't seen her. Why?
Find her. Now.
What?
Where is she?
I don't know.
She's here. Let's go.
We can't. The brass will be there.
You don't want to fuck with me, Felix.
Take me there now.
Slow down.
Tilt your head back, please, Clem.
- Is there a problem?
- No.
Sorry.
Theresa.
May I have a word?
Sure.
I appreciate your professionalism,
but you really don't
need to bother with this,
given the change in your employment status.
The test was a sham.
The little show you and Hale put on?
Completely transparent from
a technical perspective,
clumsy to the point of making
me embarrassed for you.
- Embarrassed?
- If I saw through it,
I can only imagine what
Ford was thinking.
There were glaringly obvious markers
of human intervention in the code.
If your programmers were any good,
they'd be working for me.
And I know you and your team
were responsible for the stray
and its satellite transmission.
- Bernie...
- I don't care.
40 years ago,
Ford's partner wrote half the
code this place was founded on.
What you said in the lab was right.
We don't know how the hosts work,
and I think there's
something wrong with them.
Ford's explanation only bolsters my hunch.
The ability to deviate
from program behavior
arises out of the host's
recall of past iterations.
You're thinking there's a
connection between memory and...
And improvisation, yes.
Out of repetition comes variation.
And after countless cycles of repetition,
these hosts, they were varying.
They were on the verge
of some kind of change.
You have to know my chief concern
has always been the well-being of
this park and the people in it.
I know.
Which is why I need to show you something.
- Talk to her.
- You first.
Look, I didn't want to retire her.
I know she's, like, your friend,
or... I guess.
But... but if I didn't do it,
they... they'd just get someone else to,
and then they'd be
suspicious of me, so...
so I said yes.
But I did it for you.
Always doing things for
other people, aren't you?
Time to do one more thing.
What?
All my life, I've prided
myself on being a survivor.
But surviving is just another loop.
I'm getting out of here.
You two are going to help me.
No. Do...
Do you know how far these people will go
to protect their IP?
Every part of this building,
including the skin on your back,
is made to keep you here.
It... it'd be a suicide mission.
At first, I thought you and
the others were gods.
Then I realized you're just men.
And I know men.
You think I'm scared of death?
I've done it a million times.
I'm fucking great at it.
How many times have you died?
Because if you don't help me...
I'll kill you.
If there's a problem in the park,
should we bring a security team?
Who would we trust?
Thought I could trust you, for instance.
I'm not going to explain
myself to you, Bernard.
I was charged with safeguarding
the park's intellectual property.
Why would it be in danger?
You were the only one
who was stealing it.
Delos owns the hosts' minds,
the storylines, decades of work.
Ford never allowed any of
it to be backed up off-site.
All of this could've been destroyed.
In the event of what?
Ford is done, Bernard.
The board has indulged
him for long enough.
He is done.
The corporation was concerned
he'd destroy all of the park's
IP on his way out the door.
You think I would've let him destroy
all of the hosts, all of our work?
There's far more at stake
here than the hosts' profiles.
Do you really think the
corporation's interest here
are tourists playing cowboy?
The longer I work here,
the more I think I understand the hosts.
It's the human beings who confuse me.
This building isn't in
any survey of the park.
That's because we use hosts
to do most of the surveys.
They're programmed to ignore this place.
They literally couldn't see it
if they were staring right at it.
And these unregistered
hosts you told me about?
I don't know.
He may have moved them.
What's behind this door?
What door?
What is this place?
It's a remote diagnostic facility.
Ford and his partner used them
when the park was in beta.
I had no idea this one was here.
The cottage must've
been built on top of it.
But this equipment.
This is newer.
Slower than our machines
back at the mesa,
but it will render a host in a few days.
So, Ford's been making his own
hosts out here and telling no one.
What's the matter?
Um...
Have you seen these?
What is this, Bernard?
Doesn't look like anything to me.
They cannot see the
things that will hurt them.
I've spared them that.
Their lives are blissful.
In a way, their existence
is purer than ours,
freed of the burden of self-doubt.
No, no, no, no. I don't understand.
You're a fucking monster.
Am I?
Well, you were the one who would
so blithely destroy all of them,
even him, I suppose.
After everything you have shared.
What the hell are you talking about?
Is that why...?
Did you tell him to...?
The intimacies were your idea,
if you will recall.
I think Bernard was glad of the company.
I'm not one.
I can't be.
My wife.
My son.
They're real.
I was a father.
My poor boy.
That's enough, Bernard.
You mustn't get yourself worked up.
I read a theory once
that the human intellect
was like peacock feathers.
Just an extravagant display
intended to attract a mate.
All of art, literature, a bit of Mozart,
William Shakespeare, Michelangelo,
and the Empire State Building...
Just an elaborate mating ritual.
Maybe it doesn't matter
that we have accomplished so much
for the basest of reasons.
But, of course, the
peacock can barely fly.
It lives in the dirt, pecking
insects out of the muck,
consoling itself with its great beauty.
I have come to think of so much
of consciousness as a burden,
a weight, and we have
spared them that.
Anxiety, self-loathing, guilt.
The hosts are the ones who are free.
Free here under my control.
But he's not under your control.
He brought me here to show me this.
No. He brought you here
because I asked him to.
He's been very loyal for many years.
Your time running this place
like your insane little kingdom
is over.
You've been playing God for long enough.
I simply wanted to tell my stories.
It was you people who wanted to play God
with your little undertaking.
Do you really think the
board will stand for this?
The board will do nothing.
Our arrangement is too valuable to them.
They test me every now and then.
I think they enjoy the sport of it.
This time, they sent you.
Sadly, in order to restore things,
the situation demands
a blood sacrifice.
See, Arnold and I designed
every part of this place.
It was our dream.
Did you really think
I would let you take it from me?
This is what happened to Arnold?
Did you have Bernard take
him out into the woods?
No, he wasn't here in those days.
Were you, Bernard?
Like I said,
I built all of this.
I'm afraid our guest has grown weary.
Perhaps you can help her, Bernard.
No.
"And in that sleep,
what dreams may come."
Bernard.
No. No!
Please! Please!
No!
We should be getting back, Bernard.
We have a great deal of work to do
on the new storylines.