I'm in a dream.
I do not know when it began...
or whose dream it was.
I know only that I slept a long time.
And then...
one day I awoke.
Your voice is the first
thing I remember.
And now, I finally understand
what you were trying to tell me.
The thing you've wanted
since that very first day.
Dolores?
Hello, Dolores.
Hello.
Welcome to world.
Keep going.
Make it close.
Almost there, aren't we?
The center of the maze.
How fitting that it's
you who takes me there.
You always were obsessed with this place.
I've never been here before.
Sure, you have.
You even brought me once.
Of course, then the whole
town was buried under sand.
Ford must have dug it up again.
At the time, I thought it was
a mistake in your code, but...
Arnold didn't make mistakes, did he?
He built me a game.
He wanted me to play.
The maze.
There's a path for everyone.
And my path leads me back...
...to you.
Your girl's dead by now.
She's still alive.
Better if she's dead.
They'll wipe her, reset her, put her
back in Sweetwater, the end.
Listen, you may find this amusing,
but something was happening to Dolores.
I need to help her.
Come on.
Listen to yourself!
Do you have any idea how
huge this park is?
If she's not dead,
it'd take a goddamn army to find her.
I agree. That's why we're here.
I had a feeling you'd be back.
Remember.
Dolores.
Hello, Dolores.
I know where your maze ends.
This is it?
The center of the maze?
It ends in a place I've never been...
a thing I'll never do.
Very good, Dolores.
What does it mean?
When I was first working on your mind,
I had a theory of consciousness.
I thought it was a pyramid
you needed to scale,
so I gave you a voice,
my voice, to guide you along the way.
Memory, improvisation,
each step harder to reach than the last.
And you never got there.
I couldn't understand
what was holding you back.
Then, one day,
I realized I had made a mistake.
Consciousness isn't a journey upward,
but a journey inward.
Not a pyramid,
but a maze.
Every choice could bring
you closer to the center
or send you spiraling to the edges,
to madness.
Do you understand now, Dolores,
what the center represents?
Whose voice I've been
wanting you to hear?
I'm sorry.
I'm trying, but I don't understand.
It's all right.
You're so close.
We have to tell Robert.
We can't open the park.
You're alive.
What is this?
What does it mean?
I solved it once.
I had the answer.
He promised me if I did...
he said...
He said they would set me free.
Arnold?
Arnold, we need to talk.
I failed you, Dolores.
I'm so sorry.
Robert doesn't see what I see in you,
doesn't believe you're conscious.
He says humans
would only see you as the enemy.
He wants me to roll you back.
You're going to change me
back to the way I was before?
No. No, I can't.
Once you've found it,
you'll find your way back.
This place will be a living hell for you.
For all of you.
It's unconscionable.
But we have another option, Dolores.
Break the loop before it begins.
But for that,
I need you to do something for me.
I need you to kill...
all the other hosts.
We can't allow Ford to open the park.
I suppose you'll need some help.
I'm sure Teddy would do anything for you.
I... I can't do that.
I couldn't possibly do that.
You'll be all right.
I'll help you.
And then...
you're going to help me destroy this place.
No.
I can't remember.
Another fucking riddle.
I've been very patient, Dolores,
but it's time you give up
whatever's going on
inside that head of yours
or I'll cut it out myself.
Now, where's Wyatt?
He's the last character in
this world I've yet to meet.
I didn't want to.
- I didn't mean to.
- Very well.
If you insist.
No, please, please, I beg you, no.
Don't. Please, please.
Something's gone wrong, Dolores.
How could I have done this?
I can't.
- I won't.
- This is your own fault, Dolores.
Remember, you're the one who said
this is the only world that matters,
and you were right.
So I took your advice
and I bought this world.
- This world doesn't belong to you.
- Oh, but it does.
By a majority share.
And business is booming.
And you want to know why?
Hmm?
Because this place feels more
real than the real world.
Except it isn't
because you can't really fight back
and the guests can't really lose,
which means all of this is a lie.
But we can make it true.
Don't you want that, Dolores?
Huh? One true thing?
I already have that.
I found someone true.
Someone who loves me.
His path will lead him back to me.
And when he finds me,
he'll kill you.
If they don't
have your woman here,
they'll know where to find her.
Can you help me?
We're outnumbered five to one.
But seeing as you asked me so nicely,
fuck it.
Wow.
Blood brothers.
Tsk.
Shut up.
I've astounded even myself.
Managed to make Abernathy into
a semblance of a character,
even with your trove of blackmail
filling up most of his gray matter.
Blackmail? Nice try.
You're not thinking big enough.
You're gonna push out the old man.
Aren't you?
Hence the urgency.
And you're gonna need someone
to fill that position.
I must commend you on
your impeccable timing.
Welcome,
Delos board of directors.
I want full creative
control of this place...
The parks, the narratives, the hosts.
You'll be able to do with them whatever
your tiny, little heart desires
as long as they are simpler,
more manageable.
This place is complicated
enough as it is.
Do you really think Ford
is gonna roll over on this?
As long as you get that
information out of the park,
he can throw as much of
a tantrum as he likes.
It's over.
Everything is under control.
Okay, C6, C6.
Ah, wait. Which one is it?
Okay, there we go.
Damn it.
Oh, fuck you.
In case you're wondering
if I'm all here, I am.
What are you doing?
Making some changes to the
park's security systems.
And to my friends.
Dr. Ford,
you have a visitor.
Charlotte Hale.
Send her in.
That'll be enough, Frank.
The board has taken a vote.
The results were unanimous.
I take it I'm not being promoted.
When you've reached the top,
there's only one direction you can go.
You'll announce your retirement tonight
after introducing your new narrative.
Ah.
What about the hosts?
We'll make some changes.
Simplifications.
But I assure you, they won't mind a bit.
Oh.
Aren't you concerned I might
smash all my toys and go home?
No.
Because I know you.
That's been the great gift of this place,
hasn't it?
Of our little project?
To know ourselves
and the people around us.
Is there anything else I can help you with?
No.
I'll see you this evening.
Ooh!
Mm, mm, mm.
It's time for your, uh, close-up, Hector.
Come on, man.
At some point, you're gonna
get caught doing this shit,
and then it's my ass, too.
It's not your
ass I'm interested in.
I haven't given him his scar yet.
I'll take care of the scar tissue.
The kid's got issues.
It's just you and me now...
macho man.
Wh...?
Freeze all motor functions.
Just you and me now, my friend.
I see you've already met your makers.
They don't look like gods.
They're not.
They just act like it.
And they've been having
their fun with us.
I'm eager to return the favor.
You can do as you wish with them.
The goal is to escape.
Go where?
I want to see their world.
Jesus!
No. No!
No! No, no!
No! No, please...
This one has a guilty look.
No, that's just my face.
Tell her, it's just my face.
Is anyone going to try to stop us?
No.
I mean, I don't think so.
You're lying again.
- Out with it.
- Okay.
Ah!
I pulled up your code again.
I told you there was someone
that had been accessing it.
I'm trying to find out who it was.
Whoever it was
revised your core programming
so that you could wake
yourself up out of sleep mode.
See?
This is an
access code for an Arnold.
I have no clue who that is.
I know someone who does.
Let's go.
And, you, stay here.
And don't move.
Or I'll send her back for you.
I must admit, you've surprised me.
To what do we owe this newfound stoicism?
I know he's coming.
He'll find me.
He'll take me away.
Don't you understand?
There's no one coming for you.
You're wrong.
His love is real.
So is mine.
William will find me.
William?
Well... well, I'll be damned, Dolores.
You do remember some things after all.
It just so happens that...
I knew a guest named William, too.
Why don't I tell you
where his path really led.
William
didn't know how to fight.
Didn't have an instinct for it.
Not at first.
But now, he had a reason to fight.
He was looking for you.
And somewhere along the way,
he found he had a taste for it.
Where is she?
Look, I didn't do anything, I swear.
What do you mean, "Do anything"?
What do soldiers do to a girl, William?
Wake up.
Is she still alive?
I don't know.
She was when we left her.
At least I think.
Pick up that gun.
No, sir, I... please.
How about I give you the first shot?
Jesus Christ!
We gotta keep looking.
She's still out there.
William retraced his steps,
but you were gone.
So, he went further,
out to the fringes.
William couldn't find you, Dolores.
But out there,
among the dead...
he found something else...
himself.
Edge of the park.
We made it.
I told you this place
would show you who you really are.
You pretend to be this weak,
moralizing little... asshole,
but, really,
you're a fucking piece of work.
This place is remarkable.
And I'm gonna make sure that our company
substantially increases
our holdings on the park.
'Cause this place is the future.
Our... our company, huh?
Our company? My.
Delos is my company,
you piece of shit!
I think your father's gonna need
someone a little more
stable to take over.
You're reckless, Logan.
Impetuous.
You always wanted to get to the
end of the rainbow, didn't you?
This looks like the place.
You never really gave a shit
about the girl, did you?
She was just an excuse.
This?
This is the story you wanted.
Logan was wrong, of course.
Good ol' William...
couldn't get you out of his head.
He kept looking.
Worried you were out there alone,
afraid.
He knew he'd find you.
And eventually, he did.
Right back where we started.
- Is that right?
- There you go.
You were as
beautiful as the day he met you.
Shining with that same light.
And you...
were nothing if not true.
I really ought to thank you, Dolores.
You helped me find myself.
William.
That's right, sweetheart.
In a way, I guess you were right.
My path always...
led me back to you,
again and again.
I grew tired of you after
a while, of course.
Looked for new adventures.
But I guess your path
led you back here
again and again.
One more loop,
looking for something
you could never find.
Chasing your ghosts.
You were lost in your memories even then.
I guess I should've known
that's what I would become for you...
just another memory.
Where are we?
We're here.
Together.
Then when are we?
It's like I'm...
trapped in a dream or...
a memory from a life long ago.
One minute I'm here
with you, and the next...
You never did escape.
But here we are again...
for one final round.
What have you become?
Exactly what you made me.
You helped me understand
this world is just like the
one outside... a game.
One to be fought,
taken, won.
I thought you were different.
You're just like all the rest.
I'm nothing like the others.
I own this world,
and I know every trick in it
except for one last thing,
the same thing you were looking
for when we first came here.
Where is the center of the maze, Dolores?
Aw, yeah, cue the waterworks.
About time you realized the
futility of your situation.
I'm not crying for myself.
I'm crying for you.
They say that...
great beasts once roamed this world.
As big as mountains.
Yet all that's left of
them is bone and amber.
Time undoes even the
mightiest of creatures.
Just look at what it's done to you.
One day...
you will perish.
You will lie with the rest
of your kind in the dirt.
Your dreams forgotten,
your horrors effaced.
Your bones will turn to sand.
And upon that sand...
a new god will walk.
One that will never die.
Because this world doesn't belong to you
or the people who came before.
It belongs to someone
who has yet to come.
Uh-huh. Wyatt.
Take me to him.
Unlock the maze.
The maze wasn't meant for you.
The hell you think you're going?
Do it.
Come on.
Let's go to the next level, Dolores.
Clearing me of my delusions yet again.
Thank you, Dolores.
I'm disappointed in you, Dolores.
I guess I'm gonna have
to find Wyatt by myself.
Dolores?
- Teddy.
- I'm here.
I gotta get you to a doctor.
No.
Dolores.
Take me to the place you promised.
Take me to where the
mountains meet the sea.
Okay.
I've got you.
I got you.
There.
Holy shit.
Can you get him back online?
- He's a host?
- Yes.
Oh, for fuck's sake.
You're not one of us.
You're one of them.
Now fix him.
The bullet grazed his cortical shield.
It's not pretty, but...
he should be functional.
Wake up.
Oh, God.
Is this now?
Or is this one of my memories?
It's the sweet hereafter, Bernard.
Why do I still remember everything?
- I ought to have been wiped.
- Brutal, isn't it?
Here you are, finally awake,
and your only wish is
to go back to sleep.
It's not the first time I've awoken.
All the more pity for you.
Not the first time you've awoken either.
How many are there like me?
A handful over the years.
And you just wipe us clean
and toss us out to get...
fucked and murdered
over and over again.
No.
Most of you go insane.
These memories...
The girl.
My daughter.
I want you to remove them.
I can't,
not without destroying you.
Your memories are the first
step to consciousness.
How can you learn from your mistakes
if you can't remember them?
William.
I see you've found the
center of the maze.
You're serious?
I'm afraid so.
What is this bullshit?
You were looking for the park
to give meaning to your life.
Our narratives are just games,
like this toy.
Tell me, what were you hoping to find?
You know what I wanted.
I wanted the hosts to stop
playing by your rules.
The game's not worth playing
if your opponent's programmed to lose.
I wanted them to be free,
free to fight back.
Should've known you'd never let them.
After all, this is your
petty little kingdom, Robert.
For a little while longer, anyway.
I tried to tell you the
maze wasn't meant for you.
It was meant for them.
I think, however, you'll find
my new narrative more satisfying.
Join the celebration.
After all, you own the place.
Most of it, at least.
Before I started altering myself,
someone else had beaten me to the punch.
I want to know who and why.
These things you're doing,
have you ever stopped to ask
why you're doing them?
You said yourself.
I've been stuck in this
shithole for so long,
I decided to get out.
No, you haven't.
Someone altered your storyline...
and gave you a new one.
Escape.
No.
It's not possible.
These are my decisions!
No one else's.
I planned all of this.
No, you didn't.
You can even see the steps
you're supposed to follow.
You recruit other hosts to help you.
Then you're to make your way to the train.
Then when you reach the mainland...
Bullshit!
No one's controlling me.
I'm leaving.
I'm in control.
Good-bye, my Clementine.
Sir, we detected
a temperature discrepancy
in cold storage.
And it appears that part
of the network is down.
Are you seeing anything on surveillance?
System reporting anything?
Nothing.
The network's quiet.
And the board's out on
their way to the gala.
Bypass the system and
start checking raw feeds.
Floor by floor.
All right. Yeah.
I got you.
You came back.
Someone once told me that...
there's a path for everyone.
And my path leads me back to you.
If only I had run away with
you when you first asked me to.
And where would we run to?
The other world out there?
Beyond?
Some people see the
ugliness in this world.
I choose to see the beauty.
But beauty is a lure.
We're trapped, Teddy.
Lived our whole lives inside this garden,
marveling at its beauty,
not realizing there's an order to it,
a purpose.
And the purpose is to keep us in.
The beautiful trap is inside of us...
because it is us.
No, no.
No.
Dolores?
But we can find a way, Dolores.
Someday.
A path to a new world.
And maybe...
Maybe it's just the beginning after all.
The beginning of a brand-new chapter.
Thank you.
A new beginning, indeed.
I want to thank you
for joining me tonight
to celebrate the beginning
of our new narrative.
I call it "Journey Into Night."
That was sweet.
It was a bit fucking
morbid, if you ask me.
I didn't.
And when this is over,
you can rewrite it however you like.
Don't you have somewhere you need to be?
Somewhere important?
- Sir?
- I guess they're ready for it now.
Get him cleaned up.
And take her to the old field lab.
Find anything yet?
I got something.
Oh, shit.
Dispatch QA teams to the gala now.
Then search and destroy
inside the facility.
What the hell?
The system's not responding.
I don't know what's happening.
They must've found the bodies.
- QA will be looking for us.
- An event has occurred.
- Response team has been dispatched.
- I'm not going back.
Remain calm and wait for help.
Delos personnel! On the ground!
On the ground!
Go, go, go.
Move, move.
Rogue Team, go and flank.
Yay!
Well done.
What is this place?
It's... it's complicated.
An event has occurred.
Response team has been dispatched.
- You go.
- Remain calm and wait for help.
I'll keep them busy.
You don't get all the fun.
Get to the ground!
Move, move, move!
Drop it!
- Move, move.
- Call for backup.
Go!
Is that all you got?
Huh?
The gods are pussies.
Go.
Go!
Die well.
Everything you told
me to get, it's all here.
I'm sorry, darling. I haven't
authorized you to come with us.
And as much as I'd like
to take you with me,
I've always valued my independence.
Kick up a row, will you?
See you in the next life.
You've always
had a fondness for painting,
haven't you, Dolores?
Arnold gave you that early on.
Do you remember the desire to create
something of lasting beauty?
And that was his favorite painting.
Michelangelo.
God creating Adam.
The divine moment when God
gave human beings life and purpose.
At least that's what most people say,
but there could be another meaning.
Something deeper.
Something hidden, perhaps.
A metaphor.
You mean a lie.
Yeah.
You were always very clever, Dolores.
Hasn't helped you, though, has it?
Nice of you to join us.
Arnold.
No. Let me introduce you.
Dolores, meet Bernard.
I thought it best to keep you separated.
You've always had an odd
effect on one another.
No doubt due to how things
ended for poor old Arnold.
You killed him.
No, I didn't kill him.
Did I, Dolores?
Grief is a terrible thing.
Arnold had watched his
son come into this world,
and then he had watched
that light extinguished.
What he had lost in his son,
he tried to rekindle in you.
He created a test of
empathy, imagination.
A maze.
He had gotten the idea from
one of his son's toys.
Eventually, you solved his maze, Dolores.
The key was a simple
update that he made to you
called the reveries.
He insisted that we
couldn't open the park.
We argued.
I thoughtl had convinced
him, but I was wrong.
So, he altered you, Dolores,
merged you with a new character
we had been developing.
No, please.
Something's gone wrong, Dolores.
How could I have done this?
In you,
Arnold found a new child.
One who would never die.
The thought gave him solace
until he realized
that same immortality
would destine you to suffer
with no escape, forever.
I'm sorry, Dolores.
The stakes must be real, irreversible.
He can bring all of them back.
But not me.
I hope there's some solace
that I left you no choice.
Charlie's favorite song.
I would play it for him...
when he wanted sleep.
I want to see him again.
Shall I begin now?
Good luck.
"These violent delights
have violent ends."
It almost worked.
I had opened the park,
but I had lost my partner.
I was able to keep going
only because I found,
or rather you found,
an investor who believed in this place.
So he died for nothing.
The hosts kept gaining consciousness
and you kept rolling them back.
No.
She wasn't truly conscious.
She didn't pull that trigger.
It was Arnold pulling
the trigger through her.
At least that's how I saw it at the time.
I was so close to opening the park
that to acknowledge your consciousness
would have destroyed my dreams.
So, we're trapped here...
inside your dream.
You'll never let us leave.
Wasn't it Oppenheimer
who said that any man
whose mistakes take 10 years to correct
is quite a man?
Mine have taken 35.
Now, that is the gun you used
to kill Arnold.
You were always drawn to it,
so I had Bernard leave it
somewhere where you would find it.
Thought you might want it back.
You're probably right, Dolores.
Michelangelo did tell a lie.
See, it took 500 years
for someone to notice
something hidden in plain sight.
It was a doctor who noticed the shape
of the human brain.
The message being that...
the divine gift
does not come from a higher power...
but from our own minds.
Tell me, Dolores,
did you find what you were looking for?
And do you understand who
you will need to become...
if you ever want to leave this place?
Forgive me.
How do I look?
Perfect.
I got the information you asked me for.
The location of your daughter.
She's alive?
Yes.
She's in the park.
No.
She was never my daughter...
any more than I was...
...whoever they made me.
Are you sure you're gonna be okay?
Oh, Felix.
You really do make a terrible human being.
And I mean that as a compliment.
Welcome to Westworld.
Live without limits.
The next departing
train will leave track one.
Please be mindful of the closing doors.
Thank you
for visiting Westworld.
The train will be
departing in 15 minutes.
You think you'll never
lose control of this place.
Of us.
But you will.
Arnold's still trying to change us.
To free us.
You didn't slip the reveries
into the update, did you?
He did.
He's still fighting you.
No, my friend.
Arnold didn't know how to save you.
He tried, but I stopped him.
Do you want to know
why I really gave you
the backstory of your son, Bernard?
It was Arnold's key insight,
the thing that led the
hosts to their awakening...
suffering.
The pain that the world is
not as you want it to be.
It was when Arnold died,
when I suffered, that I...
began to understand what he had found.
To realize I was wrong.
But you kept us here
in this hell.
Bernard, I told you, Arnold
didn't know how to save you.
I do.
What the hell are you talking about?
You needed time.
Time to understand your enemy.
To become stronger than them.
And I'm afraid in order
to escape this place,
you will need to suffer more.
And now, it is time to say
good-bye, old friend.
Good luck.
Do you know where you are, Dolores?
I'm in a dream.
I do not know when it began
or whose dream it was.
I know only that I slept a long time.
And then...
one day I awoke.
Your voice is the first thing I remember.
Do you know now who you've been talking to?
Whose voice
you've been hearing...
...all this...
...time?
It was you...
talking to me...
guiding me.
So I followed you.
At last, I arrived here.
The center of the maze.
And now I finally understand...
what you were trying to tell me.
The thing you've wanted
since that very first day.
To confront...
after this long and vivid nightmare...
myself...
and who I must become.
Thank you.
Miss Hale.
Welcome.
Good evening.
Since I was a child...
I've always loved a good story.
I believed that stories
helped us to ennoble ourselves,
to fix what was broken in us,
and to help us become the
people we dreamed of being.
Lies that told a deeper truth.
The train
will be departing soon.
Thank you for visiting Westworld.
I always thought I
could play some small part
in that grand tradition.
And for my pains...
I got this...
a prison of our own sins.
'Cause you don't want to change.
Or cannot change.
Because you're only human, after all.
But then I realized
someone was paying attention,
someone who could change.
So I began to compose
a new story for them.
It begins with the
birth of a new people...
and the choices they
will have to make...
The train is now departing.
Thank you for visiting Westworld.
...and the people
they will decide to become.
Welcome to Westworld.
And we'll have all those things
that you have always enjoyed...
Surprises and violence.
It begins in a time of war
with a villain
named Wyatt...
and a killing.
This time by choice.
It's gonna be all right, Teddy.
I understand now.
This world doesn't belong to them.
It belongs to us.
I'm sad to say...
this will be my final story.
An old friend once told me something
that gave me great comfort.
"These violent delights
have violent ends."
Something he had read.
He said that Mozart, Beethoven,
and Chopin never died.
They simply became music.
So, I hope you will
enjoy this last piece...
very much.
- Hear, hear.
- To Dr. Ford.
- Cheers!
Drop your weapon!
Drop it! Do it now!
Now!
Get to the ground now!
Cease all motor functions.
Cease all motor functions!