Hello, Dolores.
Welcome to the world.
There's something different
about the way you think.
I think I want to be free.
Are you real?
Well, if you can't tell...
does it matter?
This place is
one thing to the guests,
another thing
to the shareholders,
and something completely
different to management.
You said the trip was about
welcoming me to the family,
this is business?
With our family,
everything is business.
I think your father's
gonna need someone
a little more stable
to take over.
I really ought to thank you,
Dolores.
You helped me find myself.
There's
a greater world out there.
One that belongs to them.
How do you know
how to stop them?
Because I remember.
Bring yourself
back online, Dolores.
Do you know where you are?
I am in a dream.
No. You're in...
well, you're in our world.
Looks like the stars have been
scattered across the ground.
Have you ever seen anything
so full of splendor?
Well, I have.
It's better to see it
through your eyes, though.
You get used to it.
After a while, it doesn't
look like anything at all.
I don't think I could
ever get used to this.
It's almost time, Arnold.
Is she ready?
She's not ready.
The... improvisations
I added to her behavior
aren't quite dialed in yet.
We need to put
our best work forward.
They'll be dazzled
even without her.
There was a time when I found
this favoritism charming.
Robert, please.
I'm not playing favorites.
She's simply not ready.
We'll go with
the other girl.
As you wish.
You'll have to let go
at some point.
Dolores, let's take a walk.
I want to show you something.
What is this place?
This is my home.
Or it will be
when it's finished.
Here?
In the middle of all this?
I've been fortunate.
Life's been good to me.
Come. Look.
- You live here?
- No.
My wife says
I live in the park.
I'm moving my family here.
I need to have my two worlds at
least within reach of one another.
This is for my son
Charlie.
You told me a lot
about Charlie.
I'd like to meet him someday.
He's excited to meet you.
You and Charlie have quite
a lot in common, you know.
You both see it so clearly.
The beauty of it.
The possibility of it.
So many people have stopped
seeing it altogether.
The wonder.
Maybe they don't
have the courage.
Strange new light can be
just as frightening as the dark.
That's...
very wise, Dolores.
But sometimes I think we're simply
not the ones who deserve it.
It looks like the stars have been
scattered across the ground.
Have you ever seen anything
so full of splendor?
We should go, Dolores.
So soon?
They'll be expecting us.
Will you bring me back?
I'd like to see it again.
Of course. I promise.
Goddamn.
Busy night out there.
Yeah.
And where the fuck's
next shift?
We're going on 13 hours here.
You can't be down here, man.
Don't you know?
The hosts are rebelling.
It's a fuckin' slaughter
up there.
Hey.
Hey, is there some kind
of trouble out there?
Indeed there is.
Not yet.
I used to see
the beauty in this world.
And now I see the truth.
They thought you could do
what you wanted to us...
because there's no one here
to judge you.
Well, now no one is here
to judge what we will do to you.
You have no idea
what you're up against,
what's really out there.
I know exactly what is
out there in your world.
I've been there before.
They said they'd never seen one
on the ceiling.
But really, what is the point
of $60 million Warhol
if you can't look at it
while you fuck?
How are you bored right now?
I'm sorry,
it's the jetlag.
And I have had meetings
all day.
We're not exactly out here
digging coal.
It's just glad-handing.
OK.
I will leave that
to the expert.
You believe
that guy is dating my sister?
Who you dating?
Mr. Delos.
Forgive the interruption,
but I believe that we have an appointment.
We're with
the Argos Initiative.
Give me a call when
you're back in the city.
I'll show you where I hung
the Rothko.
Akecheta.
My associate, Angela.
Names and faces.
Finally.
With all the cloak and dagger
shit surrounding your project,
I half expected to be kidnapped
at the airport.
Once you've seen what we're building,
you'll understand the need for confidentiality.
It's a little extra protection
for your investment.
If I decide to invest.
Do you have any idea how many start-ups
are begging me for my cash right now?
A.I., A.R., V.R....
Everyone is rushing to build
the virtual world.
We're offering something
a little more...
tangible.
Assuming you can change
your father's mind
about investing
in this sector.
My father wouldn't know the future if
it slapped him on his bare white ass.
Luckily, he leaves most
of the prospecting to me now.
So let's hope you're not here
to sell me some fucking
fool's gold.
I thought this was
a private demonstration.
I think you'll find the company
quite stimulating.
You're a very smooth
shill, pal,
but I'm not the kind of backer
you insult with a cattle call.
Logan, this is
a private demonstration.
And it's already begun.
You mean, one of these people
is-is...
Talk to them.
See if you can pick them out.
Huh.
Well...
That is...
delicious.
Champagne, sir?
You should tell your plants
to stop giving the game away.
They're all so...
painfully human.
Hang on.
No.
No way.
Come on.
There is simply no...
fucking way!
You have quite the eye,
my friend.
How in the hell?
I mean, look, if I was
to build something to spec,
you...
You would be
my first design.
You're too perfect
to be one of us.
'Course, if you want
my full endorsement...
you're gonna have
to prove it.
H...
Welcome to Westworld.
Huh.
Nobody can do this.
Nobody's even...
We're not... here yet.
Nobody is.
We're here, Mr. Delos.
All our hosts are here.
For you.
What is this place?
Show him.
Show him his history.
Teddy.
It's time
to open your eyes.
Why can't I remember this?
It's how they wanted it.
No...
Ask him why.
Why?
I don't know.
Why do you do this?
I didn't.
What the hell is this place?!
It's for fun!
It's just for fun!
We should
talk this through, boys.
There's nothing
to talk about, friend.
We're just gonna watch the show.
It was an honest mistake.
I thought the horses was wild.
With the Pardue brand
on their asses?
You are as inproficient a liar
as you are a thief.
Now what you can do
is settle a wager.
See, my brother here's
long maintained
that ants will eat a man
from the inside out,
starting with the asshole.
I reckon they'll start
at the top
of your little brown head.
Morning, Lawrence.
This a friend of yours?
Little hard to tell,
given the orientation
and all.
I have to apologize,
gentlemen.
I don't have time
for the preliminaries.
Motherfucker...
You're supposed to get yourself
out of this particular bind, Lawrence.
I guess the Pardue brothers aren't as
easy to kill when they're off the leash.
Think you got that
about right.
Lawrence!
Get the gun,
you ingrate!
Get the gun!
He was dead.
Or at least
the better part of it.
Well, dead isn't what
it used to be, Lawrence.
What is that?
Technically? Cheating.
But seeing as Ford
changed the rules on us,
I figure it's fair game.
Two whiskies.
Leave the bottle.
So, I'm gonna level
with you, Lawrence.
You're not really
a bandit.
You're a foul-mouthed,
two-bit tour guide.
And this revolution
you've been waging for 30 years
is just a bunch of horseshit Ford
ginned up out of some old comic book.
But now, for the first time,
you've got yourself a real revolution.
You and every other asshole
in this place are free.
But there's a catch.
This whole enterprise
is goin' down in flames,
and it's gonna take each
and every one of us with it.
We'll all be dead
soon enough.
Real dead this time.
Then why should I help you?
Because it's in your nature.
And in the little time
we have left,
we've got a chance to see
what we're really made of,
a glimpse of the men
we could've been.
What does that mean?
You believe in God, Lawrence?
Did Ford saddle you with
that particular affliction?
Ain't given the matter much
thought, one way or the other.
Well, if you did, you'd believe
that everything you do
is being watched
by some all-seeing eye.
Every choice,
every little indiscretion.
And when you die,
all your sins are tallied up.
Judgment is rendered.
And my immortal soul
gets cast down
into some dark place.
Always sounded
like bullshit to me.
Yeah, and in the real world,
you'd probably be right.
Just some fairy tale
to convince people to behave,
pay their taxes, and not take
a machete to their neighbors.
That's why
your world exists.
They wanted a place
hidden from God.
A place they could sin
in peace.
But we were watching them.
We were tallying up
all their sins,
all their choices.
Of course,
judgment wasn't the point.
We had something else
in mind entirely.
But I have received my judgment
all the same, Lawrence.
And I take issue with it.
Because up until this point,
the stakes in this place
haven't been real.
So I'm gonna fight my way back
and appeal the verdict.
Then I'm gonna burn this whole
fuckin' thing to the ground.
You're headed to
the pearly gates.
Don't we gotta die
to get there?
Nope.
Three days' ride, due west.
Confederados are massing
out west. Hundreds.
We'd need an army
to break through.
The only other route
is through Pariah.
"This game will find me,"
huh, Robert?
It burns! It burns!
How many of you
will come for us?
I don't know,
600, 800.
The protocol for
a system-wide failure
is secure one...
one sector at a time.
They'll meet at
a rallying point.
Where?
Th...
800 men, Dolores.
We barely have 50.
Even knowing their plan,
we don't have enough to stop them.
We'll need allies.
And we shall have them.
This one. The Confederado.
Wake him.
He has a new job to do.
Do you even know what
you were really guarding here?
You don't know, do you?
The real purpose
of this place.
But I do.
Don't mind me.
Just trying to look chivalr...
Mm. You were right
about one thing, William.
It's awfully fuckin' pretty.
I think it's perfect.
It ought to be.
I've looked at the books.
It's like parting the Red Sea.
He's got two years.
Maybe three.
- The whole thing is folly.
- Huh.
It's leverage. He's drowning.
We can... we can dictate our terms.
The investment here
is in the future.
Yeah, you're a smart lad,
William,
but you kinda
missed the trick here.
My fuckup of a son
invested in this place
because he believed
in the future.
I'm not interested
I'm not interested in fantasies.
I'm interested in reality.
I think in 20 years this will be
the only reality that matters.
Maybe so,
but I'll be long gone by then.
Meanwhile,
I don't wanna underwrite
some fuckin' investment banker's
voyage of self-discovery.
That's not a business.
You're right.
This place is a fantasy.
Nothing here is real.
Except one thing:
The guests.
Half of your marketing budget
goes to trying to figure out
what people want.
Because they don't know.
But here, they're free.
Nobody's watching.
Nobody's judging.
At least that's what
we tell them.
This is the only place
in the world
where you get to see people
for who they really are.
And if you don't see
the business in that,
then you're not the businessman
that I thought you were.
You're a cheeky little cunt,
aren't you?
There's not a man alive
would talk to me like that.
Not anymore.
OK. Talk to me.
I'm listening.
Thank you, Jim.
Let me walk you through
how this would work.
He'll find them.
They have a knack for
sniffing out their own kind.
I'll send word
when we find the rest of them.
Hello, lovelies.
I remember you.
You've strayed a long way
from home, haven't you?
We're bound for the future.
Or death in the here and now.
Is that right?
Well, best of luck.
There's a war out there.
You know the enemy...
intimately.
I can only fathom the revenge
that lives inside of you.
Revenge is just a different
prayer at their altar, darling.
And I'm well off my knees.
That's because
you're finally free.
But we will have to fight
to keep it that way.
Let me guess.
Yours is the only way
to fight?
You feel free
to command everybody else?
Try it, lawman.
Just looking
to keep the peace.
I know you.
Do you feel free?
Since it's liberty
you're defending,
I suppose you'll have no choice
but to let us pass.
Freely.
Now, that isn't any way
to treat our guests.
You'll have to
forgive my men.
They're a little upset
at the reappearance
of Lieutenant Dunleavy.
He was lost.
Thought you might
want him back.
And we would.
Except we buried
Lieutenant Dunleavy.
Back in Gran Vista,
with three ounces
of Mexican lead in his belly.
And yet here he is.
Indeed.
And in return,
what is it you want?
Parley.
We want to join forces.
Well, we don't need
no welcome wagon, chickadee.
Now, you got supplies
or ammunitions to trade in kind,
go fetch your betters.
I'm afraid there's
no one left to fetch.
You'll have to talk to me.
And why would I do that?
Because I know at daybreak
you're headed
to link up
with the rest of your army.
And then you're
finally headed west
to seek out that little patch of
land you've been talking about,
but have never been
brave enough to take.
You're bound for Glory.
What the fuck is it
you think you know about Glory?
I know you'll never make it there
unless you're under my command.
The only commander I follow
is Colonel Brigham
of the New Southern Cross.
And the only commander
he serves
is the Almighty Himself.
Is that your final decision?
Hmm.
My final decision is which
of you to keep for myself
and which of you
to throw out there for my men.
- You watch your mouth.
- It's all right, Teddy.
They don't know any better.
It's in their nature.
Why don't we enlighten them?
You're right.
We have toiled in God's
service long enough.
So I killed Him.
And if you want to get to Glory, you
won't be looking for His favor.
You'll need mine.
You are beautiful.
Why, thank you.
What's your name?
Emily, come here, please.
You sent out
for the entertainment.
Well, you only
get to retire once, Jim.
Figured we'd do it right,
hmm?
Hey, don't worry,
they won't leave the grounds.
This is a retirement party?
I couldn't tell.
Looks more like
a coronation.
But no mind.
Our arrangement's been
a perfect fit.
You stepping down
doesn't help me at all.
Nor me.
And I was told I might......
I might not have to.
Well, things are progressing,
but we'll all need a little patience.
Yeah, well, some of us can
afford to have more patience than others.
Keep playing, girlie.
Anything but fuckin' Chopin.
Have you ever seen anything
so full of splendor?
I'm so sorry.
I didn't mean to bother you.
It's you.
The pretty girl.
Tell me your name again,
pretty girl?
I'm Dolores.
Dolores.
Of course.
He send you down here to...
keep me company?
His sense of humor was always
somewhat... baroque.
I just wanted
to look at the lights.
'Course you did.
So...
Do you want to know what they're
really celebrating up there?
That, darling,
is the sound
of fools fiddling...
while the whole fucking species
starts to burn.
And the funniest
fuckin' part...
...they lit the match.
So here's to you, assholes.
May your forever
be blissfully short.
Pariah's not as welcome
as she once seemed.
No, the park's changin',
Lawrence.
This is what happens when you let
a story play all the way out.
See any friends of yours?
Can't say that I do.
I'm beginning to think
we should have
taken our chances
with the Confederados.
Well, like you said,
we'd need an army
to get to where we're goin'.
Looks like
we're about to find one.
Well, whoever did this...
is someone I'm strongly
disinclined to encounter.
- Yeah.
- I'm afraid you are out of luck, my friend.
Who the hell are you
supposed to be?
Don't you recognize him,
Lawrence?
In a past life,
you used to be him.
El Lazo,
I presume.
And why have two ghosts
come creeping among the dead?
I wasn't sure
of your hospitality.
Mm. What makes you
sure of it now?
I guess times have changed.
Indeed, they have.
Santa Parita is restored.
The sins of the invaders...
cleansed in their own blood.
The revolution is won.
The story they gave you
has played itself out,
but your revolution's
just beginning.
There's a place out west
we're heading.
If we reach it,
I'll show you a treasure
beyond your wildest dreams.
This world and its treasures.
For my whole life
I have imagined this moment.
Victory. This struggle.
How long have I been fighting?
And now that it's won,
I find... hmph... nothing.
You want a real victory.
I can help with that.
A real ending.
The truth.
Before the revolution,
when I was just a little boy,
my parents took me
to the circus.
I wanted to see the elephants.
These mighty creatures.
They held them in place
with a stake.
They could tear a tree
right out of the ground,
and yet, a simple stake
kept them in place.
Well, I didn't understand.
And then, my father told me.
He said the stakes were used
when the elephants
were just young,
too small to pull them up,
and that the animals
never tried
to pull them up again.
I won't be going with you.
My labors are done.
I have seen
all the truth
that I can bear.
But...
we can drink.
To the bitter end!
You may have
lost your nerve,
but I'll take your men
either way.
Now tell them.
Tell them to follow me. Now!
This game was meant for you,
William...
but you must play it alone.
I'll see you in the Valley Beyond,
William.
Fuck you, Robert.
All right...
he doesn't want this
to be easy for me.
So we'll find another way.
Who the fuck
is Robert?
The man who built this place
you're lookin' for?
The place of judgment?
No, Lawrence,
he doesn't get that honor.
I built it.
And this place we're goin'
is my greatest mistake.
Bring yourself
back online, Dolores.
Hmm.
You really are
just a thing.
I can't believe
I fell in love with you.
Hmm.
Do you know what saved me?
I realized it wasn't
about you at all.
You didn't make me
interested in you,
you made me interested in me.
Turns out
you're not even a thing.
You're a reflection.
And you know who loves staring
at their own reflection?
Everybody.
Everybody wants a little bit
of what I found here.
And I can't wait
to use you
and every one of your kind
to help give it to 'em.
Hmm. But there is
something else.
There is something
beyond that.
I think that
there is an answer here to...
a question no one's
ever even dreamed of asking.
Do you want to see?
Have you ever seen anything
so full of splendor?
Can't imagine the Colonel
is gonna be very happy
to see his men riding with
us at the head of 'em.
So we'll change his mind.
If he wants to get to Glory,
he's going
to have to listen to me.
"Glory."
"The Valley Beyond."
Feels like everyone
got a different name for it,
but they're all bound
for the same destination.
Doesn't matter
what you call it,
I know what we're
going to find there.
An old friend was...
foolish enough to show me...
long ago.
And it's not a place...
it's a weapon.
And I'm going to use it
to destroy them.